Finding Aid for Nabeel Abraham papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Nabeel Abraham papers
1962-2013
Abraham, Nabeel.
2014103 Aa 2
Nabeel Abraham was a professor of anthropology and director of the Honors Program at Henry Ford Community College and an Arab American activist. Nabeel Abraham papers primarily document his focus on Arab American and Middle East issues.
29 linear feet in 27 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material was donated by Nabeel Abraham (donor no. 10156 ) in November 2013 and January 2014.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research, except for boxes 12 and 27 which contain materials that are restricted until June 1, 2035.
Nabeel Abraham was born in Charlotte, North Carolina in 1950 to Palestinian immigrant parents. In 1955 his family moved to Detroit, Michigan, home to a large Arab American community. He earned his bachelor's degree in anthropology and sociology from Wayne State University in 1972 and his master's and doctorate degrees in anthropology from the University of Michigan in 1973 and 1978, respectively.
In the years following completion of his doctoral program, Abraham engaged in a variety of positions. These included teaching at the University of Algiers, directing projects focused on outreach and services in the Arab community and the development of curriculum materials and teacher training on Arabic culture and history and Arab American heritage, and serving as executive director of the Association of Arab-American University Graduates (AAUG) and consultant to the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee (ADC).
After working as a visiting lecturer at the University of Michigan in 1984, Abraham was hired as an anthropology instructor by Henry Ford Community College (HFCC) in Dearborn in 1985. His courses included Introduction to Anthropology, Ethnology of North America, and Peoples and Cultures of the Middle East and North Africa. In 1996, he became director of HFCC's Honors Program and proceeded to redesign the program and its curriculum. While continuing to teach one anthropology course per semester, his duties included recruiting freshmen to the program, advising honors students and helping them with the transition to four-year colleges and universities, and coordinating the work of the honors faculty. Abraham retired in 2013.
In addition to his daily work at HFCC, Abraham wrote and spoke extensively on Arab American and Middle East issues. He edited and contributed to several books, wrote many papers and articles for presentations at conferences and inclusion in encyclopedias and publications such as Lies of Our Times and Middle East Report, and gave talks on these issues in many different venues.
The papers are arranged into seven series: Biographical, Topical, Writings, Dissertation, Lectures and Presentations, Printed Materials, and Audiovisual.
The Nabeel Abraham papers primarily document Abraham's interest in and research on Arab American and Middle East issues. Also present are records on his time as a student at Wayne State University and the University of Michigan and his career at HFCC.
Subjects:
Abraham, Nabeel.; American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.; Arab American scholars.; Arab Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Arab-Israeli conflict.; Henry Ford Community College.; Iraq War, 2003-2011.; Middle East--Politics and government--20th century.; Muslims--Michigan--Detroit.; Palestinian Arabs--Government policy--Israel.; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Yemeni Americans--Michigan--Detroit.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Abraham, Nabeel.; Arab Americans.; Middle East--Politics and government--20th century.; Rushdie, Salman.Satanic verses.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Abraham, Nabeel.; Chomsky, Noam.; Jabara, Abdeen, 1940-; Middle East--Politics and government--20th century.; Said, Edward W.
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; Lectures.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Biographical
  The Biographical series (0.5 linear feet) includes materials focusing on Abraham and his work, including articles, curricula vitae, photos, applications for instructor and president openings at HFCC, and biographical sketches.
  - Applications-HFCC (Henry Ford Community College) (Box 1)
    - Anthropology Instructor, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - President, 2012-2013 (Box 1)
  - Articles About, Quotes, 1971-1997; undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Curricula Vitae, circa, 1977-2004 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-2005 (Box 1)
  - Photos, 1968 undated (Box 1)
  - Sketches, 1991-2000 (Box 1)
- Topical
  The Topical series (20 linear feet), the largest of the collection, mostly contains research materials collected by Abraham relating to Arab American and Middle East issues. These materials include newspaper clippings, journal articles, and organizational newsletters related to various topics. Also present in this series are correspondence and Abraham's notes. Some of the larger topics reflected in this series include the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and the United States' role in it, 1990-1991 Gulf War, 2003 invasion of Iraq, the relationship between Islam and the West, and attacks on Arab and Muslim Americans, particularly after September 11, 2001. Also contained here are records relating to numerous Arab American organizations such as the Association of Arab-American University Graduates (AAUG), Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services (ACCESS), American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee (ADC), and Organization of Arab Students (OAS). Many files contain writings by and articles on scholars sharing the same areas of interest as Abraham, as well as his correspondence with them. Some of the more prominent of these individuals are Noam Chomsky, Edward Said, Norm Finkelstein, and Israel Shahak. A few topical files relate to Abraham's career and work.
  - 9/11, 2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 20/20, 1981 (Box 2)
  - War, 1967; 1990 (Box 2)
  - 1985 TWA (Trans World Airlines) Hijacking, 1985 undated (Box 2)
  - 10,000 Maniacs, 1987 undated (Box 2)
  - AAUG (Association of Arab-American University Graduates), 1978-2001; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Abdel-Rahman, Omar, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Abdulhadi, Rabab, 1998 undated (Box 2)
  - Abraham, Malik, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Abraham, Sameer, 1974-2002 (Box 2)
  - Abraham, Sameer-"Analysis of Arab Immigration and Adjustment in Detroit,", 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Abscam, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Abu Jihad (Assassination of), 1988 (Box 2)
  - Abu Lughod, Ibrahim, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Abu Nidal, 1983-1990 (Box 2)
  - Abu Sharif, Bassam, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Abu Taleb Killing, 1987 (Box 2)
  - ACCESS (Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services), 1976-2005; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - ACCESS (Arab Community Center for Economic and Social Services), 1976-2005 (Box 27)
    [Restricted until June 1 2035 ]
  - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union), 1998 (Box 2)
  - Adamany, David, 1989 (Box 2)
  - ADC (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee), 1981-2003 (Box 2)
  - ADC (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee), 1981-2003 (Box 27)
  - ADC (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee)-Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - ADC (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee)-Detroit Chapter, 1981-1986; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Adjunct Picnic, 2006 (Box 2)
  - ADL (Anti-Defamation League), 1978-2002; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Adoni, Lamis, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Afghanistan, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations), 1982-1988 (Box 2)
  - AFT (American Federation of Teachers) Lebanon Resolution, 2006 (Box 2)
  - AIPAC (American Israel Public Affairs Committee), 1982-1987; undated (Box 2)
  - Airplane Shoot Downs, 1983-1988 (Box 3)
  - Ajami, Fouad, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Ajrouch, Kristine, 1996-1997; undated (Box 3)
  - Ajrouch, Kristine, 1997 (Box 27)
  - Ajyal Theatrical Group, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Akawi, Mustafa, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Al-Ali, Nagi, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Alaolmolki, Nozar, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Al-Aqsa Intifada, 2000-2002; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Al-Aqsa Massacre, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Al-Faruqi, Ismail, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Algeria, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Allon Plan, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Al-Tawil, Hashim, 2004 (Box 3)
  - American Anthropological Association, circa 1982 (Box 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee, undated (Box 3)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1981 undated (Box 3)
  - American Jews, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  - American Muslim Council, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Americans for a Safe Israel, 1982-1987 (Box 3)
  - Amnesty International
    - Criticism, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous 1979-2003 on Israel and Occupied Territories, 1984-1990 (Box 3)
    - Job File, 1985-1987 (Box 27)
    - Letters/Support, 1986-1993 (Box 3)
    - Popper Massacre, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    - On Torture, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
  - Analysis-9/11/01, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Petition-People for the Reassessment of Aid to Israel (PRAI), 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Ansar Camp, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Anthrax, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology, 1989-2000 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology 409, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Arab
    - And Anti-Muslim Incidents, 2001-2004 (Box 3)
    - Crimes-Human Rights Watch, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Letters, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Muslim
    - Clampdown, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Harrassment, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1982-2005 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Terrorism Legislation, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Aquino Report, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Arab American
    - Activism, 1982 undated (Box 3)
    - Book Project with Ken Wachsberger, 1987-1991 (Box 3)
    - Community Advisory Council (Detroit), 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Educator Day, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Feminist Perspectives, 2005; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Medical Association, Michigan Chapter Directory, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Music, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Response, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Arab Americans
    - General, 1983-2007; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Fortune Magazine, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Memorandum on (Dearborn Planning Department), 1979 (Box 4)
  - Arab-Black Relations, 1982-1986 (Box 4)
  - Arab-Chaldean Community Social Services Council, 1981-1983 (Box 4)
  - Arab Denial 9/11/01, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
  - Arab Detroit
    - 9/11, 2011 (Box 4)
    - 9/11 Publicity, 2010-2012 (Box 4)
    - Book Corrections, 2000-2003 (Box 4)
    - Book Reviews, 1998-2004; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - From Margin to Mainstream, 1996-1999 (Box 4)
    - From Margin to Mainstream, 1998 undated (Box 4)
    - Map, 1983-2000 (Box 4)
    - Photos, 1996-2000; undated (Box 4)
  - Arab Human Rights Organization, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - Arab Immigration History Notes, 1987 undated (Box 4)
  - Arab Recognition of Israel, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Arab View of U.S., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Arab Women's Conference, 2010-2011 (Box 4)
  - Arab Workers' Caucus, 1973-1976; undated (Box 4)
  - Arabesque: Insights into Arab Culture, 2004 undated (Box 4)
  - Arabic Outreach Program, Wayne County Community College, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Arabic-Speaking Peoples of Metropolitan Detroit, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Arabs in the New World: Reviews, 1983-2004 (Box 4)
  - Arafat, Yasser
    - Bashing, 1985-1989 (Box 4)
    - General, 2002-2004 (Box 4)
    - Paris/Rome, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Rabin Handshake, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Rule, 1995-2002 (Box 4)
    - Statements, 1984-1994 (Box 4)
    - Stockholm, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    - Strasbourg, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Visa Denial, 1988 (Box 4)
  - ASA (American Sociological Association) Convention, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Assyrians/Chaldeans, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - ATAG (Arab Theatrical Arts Guild), 2001 (Box 27)
  - ATAG Forum, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Atrocities-U.S., 2003 (Box 4)
  - Auto Companies-Economics and Work, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Ayoub, Elias, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Bagby, Ihsan-Mosque Study, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Bangladeshis in Motown, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Barakat, Halim, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Barghouti, Mustafa, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Barlow, Betsy, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
  - BBC (British Broadcasting Corporation): Critique, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Beach Attack, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Bedouins, 1986-1998 (Box 5)
  - Begin, Menahem, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Beinen, Joel, 1990-2004 (Box 5)
  - Being and Becoming Arab-American, undated (Box 5)
  - Beirut Massacre, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Bell Curve, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Bennoune, Mahfoud, 1989-2005 (Box 5)
  - Benvenisti, Meron, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Beydoun, Ahmad, undated (Box 5)
  - Bibliographies, 1972-1973; undated (Box 5)
  - Bigotry and Discrimination, 1983-1991 (Box 5)
  - Bilingual Teacher Training, University of Michigan-Flint, undated (Box 5)
  - Bin Laden Tape, 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Bin Ladenism, 1998-2003 (Box 5)
  - Birzeit University, 1986 undated (Box 5)
  - Bizarre 9/11, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Bloom, Allan, 1987-1990 (Box 5)
  - Bonior, David, 1981-1985 (Box 5)
  - Book Reviews
    - Arab Students Quarterly, 1994 (Box 5)
    - International Migration Review, 1983-2002 (Box 5)
    - Journal of Palestine Studies, 2002 (Box 5)
    - Middle East Report, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-2003 (Box 5)
  - Boullata, Kamal, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Brink, Judy, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Broken Treaties, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Broomfield, William, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Bruzonsky, Mark, 1989 (Box 5)
  - B'Tselem, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Buchanan, Pat, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Budget Deficits, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Bush and Arab Americans, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Bush/Quayle, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
  - Bushisms, 2001-2004 (Box 5)
  - Bush's Peace Plan Text, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
  - Bush's Support for Sharon, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
  - Cabal, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Call to Prayer, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Cambodia, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Camp David, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Campaign for Peace and Democracy/East and West, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Carr, Bob, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1982-1990 (Box 5)
  - Casualties
    - Depleted Uranium, 2003 (Box 5)
    - General, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
    - Gulf War, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Cemeteries: Israeli Arab, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Census, 2000; 2000-2003 (Box 5)
  - Center for Arab American Studies, University of Michigan-Dearborn, 2006 (Box 27)
  - Center for Arab Studies, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Central America, 1990-1993 (Box 5)
  - Chaldeans, 1983-2004 (Box 5)
  - Charara, Hayan, 1998-1999; undated (Box 5)
  - Checkpoints, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Cheney, 2003 (Box 5)
  - China: Human Rights, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Chomsky, Noam (Box 6)
    - Articles About, 1985-2005 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1984-2005; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - "Equality", 1987-1988 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1988-2003; undated (Box 6)
  - Christian Fundamentalism, 1989-2004 (Box 6)
  - CIA (Central Intelligence Agency)
    - Christisons, 2003-2004 (Box 6)
    - General, 1984-1991 (Box 6)
  - Civil Liberties, 2001-2004; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Clarke, Richard, 2003-2004 (Box 6)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
  - Closures, 2003-2004 (Box 6)
  - Cluster Bombs, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Cockburn, Alex, 1989-1995 (Box 6)
  - Commentary
    - April 2002, 2002 (Box 6)
    - Sontag, et al., 2001 (Box 6)
  - Community Profile, undated (Box 6)
  - Congress, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
  - Congressional Hearing, July 16, 1986; 1986 (Box 6)
  - Conover, Ted, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
  - Conyers, John, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Middle East International, 1982-2001 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1976-1989, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - 1990-1999 (Box 6)
      - 2000-2005, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - 2006-2012, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Publishers, 1986-2004 (Box 7)
    - Sharif, Hasan, 1980-1987 (Box 7)
  - Corrie, Rachel, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Cost and Impact of Operation Desert Shield, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Covering Arab America, 1992-2003 (Box 7)
  - Crazy Right, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Crockett, George, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Cuban Missile Crisis, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Cultural Survival, 1986-1990 (Box 7)
  - Culture of Fear, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - "Days of Rage,", 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - D.C. Sniper, 2002 (Box 7)
  - de Joon, Paul, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Dearborn Politics, 1985-2004 (Box 7)
  - Dearborn Press and Guide, 2006-2013 (Box 7)
  - Death of Empathy, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Defense Planning Guide, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Deir Yassin, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Democratic Palestine, 2002-2004 (Box 7)
  - Demographic Data, 1979-2001 (Box 7)
  - Demographic Problem, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Demolitions, 1982-1992 (Box 7)
  - Deportations, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Depression, 2004 (Box 7)
  - DeRosa, "Vicars of Christ", undated (Box 7)
  - Dershowitz, Alan, 1989-2003 (Box 7)
  - Detroit Free Press
    - Editor, 1982-1990 (Box 7)
    - Editorials, 1989 (Box 7)
    - News Coverage, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Op-Eds
      - 1982-1988 (Box 7)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Detroit News, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Developments-9/11, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Dingell, John, 1987-1993 (Box 7)
  - Discrimination-1990s, 1972-1998 (Box 7)
  - Divestment, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Dix Mosque, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Dixie Chicks, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Domino Theory (L.A. Times), 2003 (Box 7)
  - Douglas, Mary, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Drug Trade, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Druze, 1981-1986 (Box 7)
  - East Timor, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Eban, Abba, 1986-1988 (Box 7)
  - Economy, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Editor: Dearborn Press and Guide, 1987-2004 (Box 7)
  - Editor: Detroit News, 1985-1995 (Box 7)
  - Editor: Miscellaneous, 1980-2004 (Box 7)
  - Editor: New York Times, 1982-1993 (Box 7)
  - Editor: NPR, 1986-2003 (Box 7)
  - Editor: Tecumseh, 2003-2004 (Box 7)
  - Egypt, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
  - Ellis, Marc, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Ellsberg, Daniel, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Emerson/Pipes, 1999-2003 (Box 8)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1983 undated (Box 8)
  - Emerson, Steven, 1990-2001 (Box 8)
  - Empire, 2000-2002; undated (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia of American Immigrant Cultures, 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Environment, 2004-2005 (Box 8)
  - Epic Encounters, undated (Box 8)
  - Eqbal, Ahmad, 1997-1998 (Box 8)
  - EU (European Union) Poll and Israel, 2003 (Box 8)
  - European Community, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Evangelical Right, 1984-1990 (Box 8)
  - Exodus, 1948; 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Expulsion, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
  - Expulsion Threats, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Lectureship Award, 1986-1989 (Box 8)
  - Fadel, Ziad, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Fakhouri, Habib, 1980-1983 (Box 8)
  - Fakhouri, Haifa, 1981-1988 (Box 8)
  - Fallujah, November 2004; 2004-2005 (Box 8)
  - Family Business, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Family, Children, and Work, 2000 (Box 8)
  - Farrakhan, Louis, 1985 (Box 8)
  - FBI (Federal Bureau of Investigation), 1984-2002 (Box 8)
  - Finkelstein, Norm
    - "Anti-Semitism", 2004-2005 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-2010; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991-2010 (Box 27)
    - Review (Unfinished), 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Trip, 2010 (Box 8)
    - University of California Press, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Fisk, Robert, 1996-2004 (Box 8)
  - Florida Incident, 2002 (Box 8)
  - FOIA (Freedom of Information Act), 1971-1996 (Box 8)
  - Fonda, Jane, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Fordson Incident, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Aid, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Investment in U.S., 1990 (Box 8)
  - Fortune Article, 2002 (Box 8)
  - France-Immigration, undated (Box 8)
  - France State Terrorism, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Free Expression-University of Michigan Record, 2002 (Box 8)
  - French-Language Materials, 1984 undated (Box 8)
  - Friedman, Thomas, 1986-1992 (Box 8)
  - Friends of UPMRC (Union of Palestinian Medical Relief Committees), 1988-1989 (Box 8)
  - From Time Immemoriam/Joan Peters, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
  - Fulbright, 1977-1981 (Box 8)
  - Funkenstein, Amos, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Future Papers/Arcticles, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - Future Scenarios, 2003 (Box 9)
  - FYI, 1992-2001 (Box 9)
  - Gary, David, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Gay Muslims, 2001-2005 (Box 9)
  - Gaza, 1986-1993 (Box 9)
  - Geertz, Clifford, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Geneva-Arafat, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Geneva Accords, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Germany/Japan, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Giammanco, Roberto, 1990-1997 (Box 9)
  - Glimmer Train, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Glossary of Occupation, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Goering, Hermann, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Goldman, Nahum, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Gould, Stephen Jay, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Grants, 1986-1998 (Box 9)
  - Green, Stephen, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - Griffin, Philip, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Guantanamo, 2003-2004; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Guernica, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Gulf Crisis
    - Arab Bashing, 1990-1993 (Box 9)
    - Commentaries, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Congress, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Diplomatic, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Dissent, 1987-1991 (Box 9)
    - Editorial/Congressional Reaction, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - The Enemy, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Israel-Iraq, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Media Coverage, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Militarism, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Nightmare Scenario, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Oil, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Palestinians, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - Polls, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
    - U.S. Isolation, 1990 (Box 9)
    - U.S. Support for Saddam, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Gulf Update, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Gulf War/FBI and INS, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
  - Gulf War: Northwest and Pan Am Discrimination, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
  - Gypsies, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Haberman, Clyde, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Haddad, Yvonne, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Haig, Al, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Halliday, Fred, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Halper, Jeff, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Hamza, Lara, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Happiness Conference, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Harassment of Arab-Americans by Israel, 1986-2000 (Box 10)
  - Harkabi, Yehoshafat, 1989 undated (Box 10)
  - Harkin, Tom, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Hasbara, 1982-1990 (Box 10)
  - Hass, Amira, 2001-2005 (Box 10)
  - Hatem, Mervat, 1999-2002 (Box 10)
  - Health, 1980-2001 (Box 10)
  - Health Needs of Arab Community Questionnaire, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Health Needs Studies, 1972-1979 (Box 10)
  - Hedges, Gaza Diary, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Herman, Ed, 1990-1998 (Box 10)
  - Hersh, Seymour, 2004 (Box 10)
  - HFCC (Henry Ford Community College)
    - Honors Notes and Letters, 1998 (Box 10)
    - Mirror News Articles, 1997-2002 (Box 10)
    - Yemeni Students Union, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Hicky, Marcelana, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Hispanics, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Historical Society of Michigan, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Hitchens, Christopher, 1981-2002 (Box 10)
  - Hobsbawm, Eric, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Hollywood and Arab Stereotypes, 1980-1990 (Box 10)
  - Holocaust, 1987-1999 (Box 10)
  - Holocaust Denial, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Houston Arabs, 1974-1986 (Box 10)
  - Howell, Sally, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Human Disaster, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
  - Human Rights Watch, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
  - Hussein, Kamal, 2003 (Box 10)
  - IAS (Institute of Arab Studies) Fellowship, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
  - ICAHD (Israeli Committee Against House Demolitions), 2002 (Box 10)
  - ICP (International Center of Photography), 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - Illegality of the War, 2003 (Box 10)
  - ILO (International Labor Organization), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Immigration Data and INS Materials, 1974-2001 (Box 10)
  - Imperial Designs, 2002 (Box 10)
  - In America/Echo, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Institute for Social Research-Detroit Arab-American Survey, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Institute of Arab Studies, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Internet, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Interviews Post 9/11, 2001-2002 (Box 10)
  - Intifada-U.S. Weapons, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Intro to Sociology 31, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Invarianti, 1989-1991 (Box 10)
  - Iraq, 1982-2003 (Box 10)
  - Iraq and Arab Americans, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Iraq Resolution/HFCC, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
  - Iraqi Bomb, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Iraqi Nukes and Missiles, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Iraqi Shi'a, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Isaac, Rael Jean, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Islam, undated (Box 10)
  - Islam in America, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Islam and Science, 2002 (Box 10)
  - Islam and Women, 1990-2002 (Box 10)
  - Islamic
    - Center of Detroit, 1988; 2001-2002 (Box 10)
    - Fundamentalism, 1990-1998; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Terrorism, 1983-1993 (Box 10)
    - Theology, 1989 undated (Box 10)
  - Israel/Israeli
    - Air and Sea Hijackings, 1985-1986; undated (Box 10)
    - Arabs, 1980-1989 (Box 10)
    - Arms Dealing, 1984-1992 (Box 10)
    - Attack on Lebanon, May 1996; 1994-1996 (Box 10)
    - Consulate in Detroit, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Criticism of, 1982-1993 (Box 11)
    - Death Squads, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Demographics, 1985-1987 (Box 11)